<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kevin Golding</title>
    <link>http://kgolding.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Kevin Golding</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://kgolding.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>http://kgolding.com/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kgolding.com/intro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello! I&amp;rsquo;m a software and hardware developer/designer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shopping mail call recording</title>
      <link>http://kgolding.com/project/shopping-mail-call-recording/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kgolding.com/project/shopping-mail-call-recording/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radio signal recording at sea</title>
      <link>http://kgolding.com/project/radio-signal-recording-at-sea/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kgolding.com/project/radio-signal-recording-at-sea/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Portrait Gallery (NPG)</title>
      <link>http://kgolding.com/project/national-portait-gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kgolding.com/project/national-portait-gallery/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Working with two-way radio dealer &lt;a href=&#34;http://walltowallcomms.co.uk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wall to Wall Communications Ltd&lt;/a&gt; and using my
&lt;a href=&#34;http://smc-gateway.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SMC Gateway&lt;/a&gt; product, we provided three key integrations to aid in the safety of staff and vistors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All three integrations were engineered using one standard off the shelf &lt;a href=&#34;http://smc-gateway.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SMC Gateway&lt;/a&gt;, making
the material cost low, and by using the built-in graphical application builder no software development was required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;fire-alert-alarm-notification&#34;&gt;Fire alert/alarm notification&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The existing fire alarm system was integrated using its serial printer port. Messages are inspected by the Gateway
and high priority ones are sent to the staff on their &lt;a href=&#34;http://hytera.co.uk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hytera&lt;/a&gt; DMR radios.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;art-protection-alarm-notification&#34;&gt;Art protection alarm notification&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gallery has a sophisticated alarm system that monitors all of the pieces of art and pictures for multiple
conditions including temperature, movement, vibration and more. Using XML over TCP/IP the Gateway receives alarms,
which are sent to different security personal depending on the location of the alarm. This lets staff quickly respond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;telephony-integration-of-mitel-pabx-to-hytera-two-way-radios&#34;&gt;Telephony integration of Mitel PABX to Hytera two way radios&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the event of an issue requiring the attendance of third partys such as the emergency services, the Gateway provides
the means for a two-radio user to make (and receive) a telephone call via the galleries Mitel telephone system.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solutionbase Ltd</title>
      <link>http://kgolding.com/solutionbase-ltd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2014 12:09:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kgolding.com/solutionbase-ltd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Solutionbase Ltd is my company that provides:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Software and hardware design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two-radio integration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Web hosting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Email services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recognised as an application partner with Motorola (MOTOTRBO), Hytera (DMR Tier II &amp;amp; Tier II), Kenwood, Tait,
&amp;amp; Simoco, we can design custom solutions as projects, or provide solutions under license.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Solutionbase Ltd support please email &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:support@solutionbase.co.uk&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;support@solutionbase.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wirefree IP Ltd</title>
      <link>http://kgolding.com/wirefree-ip-ltd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2009 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kgolding.com/wirefree-ip-ltd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I co-founded &lt;a href=&#34;http://wirefreeip.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wirefree IP Ltd&lt;/a&gt; which is a trade only provider of IP wireless links mainly within the electronic security
industry. The company provides a turn-key solution at fixed prices for security installers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our links are custom made, using a combination of third party antennas and wireless transceiver&amp;rsquo;s. Each link is
installed, commissioned, tested and presented to the security installer as a &amp;lsquo;virtual ethernet cable&amp;rsquo; taking away
the complexities of encryption, IP routing etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>POS Ltd</title>
      <link>http://kgolding.com/project/POS-Ltd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 1998 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kgolding.com/project/POS-Ltd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;POS Ltd was the only third party service provider for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Psion_(company)&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PSION&lt;/a&gt;
range of PDA&amp;rsquo;s (active in the late nineties and noughties).
The company provided a repair service to end users and to the trade alike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the company expanded in line with the massive success of PSION, the various spreadsheets that were used to track
repairs became unwieldily and were slowing down the repair process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was commissioned to create a service management system to handle the entire process from booking in, repair,
and booking out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I built an Intranet system using PHP &amp;amp; MySQL, and the system was used successfully for the next decade with very little
maintenance. The system allowed admin staff to book in repairs that were displayed to the engineers for repair.
Engineers could record serial numbers, parts used etc and once repaired admin staff arranged the return of the
PDA&amp;rsquo;s to the customer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://kgolding.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kgolding.com/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a programmer and hardware designer!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since way back in 1982 when I first wrote a port of space invaders for the ORIC-1 in BASIC with embedded 6502 machine
code for the graphics scrolling I&amp;rsquo;ve been interested and active in software and hardware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much of my early working career was in the electronic security and fire detection industry, having
worked for the likes of Honeywell, Tyco &amp;amp; ADT. I have had plenty of experience across the board including IP CCTV.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst my career choices were always in technology, I only started professionally programming in 1998 mainly putting
together websites and working with design companies as part of the .com boom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I progressed onto creating web delivered applications starting with a service management system in 1998 for a
South London company who repaired personal organisers. This lead on to a decade of writing various solutions mainly
for small local businesses. The principle of delivering application via a web browser has held me in good stead and
continues to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These days, much of my time is spent on the continued development of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://smc-gateway.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SMC Gateway&lt;/a&gt; which
is sold under license by &lt;a href=&#34;http://smc-comms.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SMC Ltd&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>